Himanshu Pahadia

Innovation **Engineer**

Associate Innovation Engineer at Zenlabs, Zensar Technologies Pune. Maharashtra, India

Portfolio | himanshupahadia.me

(+91) 9654 3187 90 himanshu.pahadia@gmail.com

Skills

Concepts and Technologies - Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality, Computer Graphics

Programming Languages - Python, Java, C/C++, C#, JavaScript, BluePrint Visual Scripting, HTML, CSS

Tools and Libraries - TensorFlow, Android SDK, Unity3D, Unreal Engine 4, Google VR SDK, Vuforia SDK, Autodesk 3ds Max, Blender, OpenCV, OpenGL, Soot Analysis, Django, Flask, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro), Proto.io

Experience

Zensar Technologies Associate Innovation Engineer

June 2018 - Present, Pune

Currently working as an Associate Innovation Engineer at Zenlabs. I'm researching in the computer vision, deep learning and human-computer interaction. I'm also working on developing augmented reality and virtual reality experiences and how to make them as realistic as possible.

Zensar Technologies Research and Development Intern

May 2017 - June, 2017, Pune

Worked as a research intern in Zenlabs, The R&D center and Innovation hub of Zensar Technologies. I implemented a prototype system for providing gesture, voice and face recognition in a retail system. Developed a Virtual reality POC for the labs. Research involved in the Computer vision, Augmented Reality and Virtual Reality domain. I got a pre-placement offer during the internship.

Uber Graphic design Intern

June 2016 - August 2016, Delhi

Worked as a Graphic Design intern at Uber. Designed multiple promotional posters for Uber's Loyalty Program using Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop.

IIIT Delhi Research Intern

May 2015 - July 2015, Delhi

Worked with Dr. Ojaswa Sharma, IIIT Delhi on **Virtual Campus Project**, a 3D interactive and immersive virtual/mixed reality environment of IIIT Delhi campus designed to support geospatial services including smart navigation and telepresence. I was responsible for developing the 3D model of the campus rendering contours, terrain and virtual walkthrough in CryEngine. I developed the project website too.

Research Statement

My research interests lie at the intersection of Computer Vision, Deep Learning and human computer interaction. In particular, my focus is on the development of new interaction techniques and their application to problems of emerging technologies like Virtual Reality and Augmented Reality. I have a keen interest in developing VR and AR experiences too.

Education

IIIT-Delhi Bachelor of Technology

August 2014 - August 2018, Delhi

Majored in Computer Science & Engineering

CGPA: 7.47

Amrita Vidyalayam Senior School

June 2014. Delhi

Science stream, CBSE

CGPA: 9.5

Selected Projects

3D Campus Model using Google Sketchup

August 2014 - December 2014, Team Size - 3

Guide - Dr. Saket Anand

Developed the 3D model of IIIT-Delhi using Google Sketchup.

Smart Automotive Bot

January 2015 - April 2015, Team Size - 2

Guide - Dr. Jyoti Sinha

An Intelligent car powered by Raspberry Pi which that follows traffic light, avoids obstacles and detects platform edge.

Detective Facebook

August 2015 - November 2015, Team Size - 2

Guide - Dr Chetan Arora

Developed a web application using Java servlets and Java libraries that predict profile likes for new posts using past data and linear regression.

Depixelize Pixel art

October 2016 - November 2016, Team Size - 2

Guide - Dr Ojaswa Sharma

A program that converts small pixel art into beautiful anti-aliased vector representations. It is an implementation of a paper by Johannes Kopf and Dani Lischinski.

Project Lazy Pizza

February 2017 - April 2017, Team Size - 3

Guide - Dr Ponnurangam Kumaraguru

Designed a platform that crowdsources the food delivery system within IIIT Delhi campus by implementing a barter system and a virtual currency.

Interactive Swept Surface Modeling in Virtual Reality

February 2018 - April 2018, Team Size - 2 Guide - Dr Ojaswa Sharma

An interactive VR application that allows the user to sweep surfaces in virtual environment using both the motion-tracked controllers. It is an implementation of a paper by Tim McGraw, Esteban Garcia and Drew Summer (Purdue University).

Community Work

Health Fitness Trust Teaching Volunteer

December 2011 - January 2018, Delhi

I volunteered as a teacher in a Minority group skill enhancement project at the NGO (partnered by Ministry of Minority Affairs) - teaching the students english, soft skills, computer science and career enhancement skills.

Positions of responsibilities

Ink. (Design club) - Club Coordinator
Odyssey'18 - Creatives Head, Organizing committee
UX design winter school'17 - Teaching Assistant
Esya'16 (Technical fest) - Creatives Head, Organizing committee
Design 360 (IIIT Delhi's first designathon), Odyssey'17 - Event head
TEDxIIITD'16 - Design Head
Media Panel (Official content to IIITD) - Head, Design team
Cadence'16 - Event organizer, Organizing team
Esya'15 - Organizing team
Odyssey'15 (Cultural fest) - Organizing team

Github

https://github.com/pahadiahimanshu

Esya'14 - Volunteer